So in the last lecture, we identified the layout of the application and that component tree here,
Bu nedenle son derste, uygulamann ve bu bileen aacnn dzenini burada tespit ettik.
that's of course a super important step.
Tabii ki ok nemli bir adm.
Now this is only one part,
imdi bu sadece bir blm.
we also need to know which state we're going to use in our application.
Hepimizin uygulamanzda hangi devletin kullanlacan bilmemiz gerekir.
This state becomes important because it also allows us to identify what should be a component and what
Bu devlet nemlidir, nk neyin bir bileeni ve ne olmas gerektiini
should be a container.
belirlememizi salar.
So what should be a stateless component and what should be a stateful component.
Peki devlet daha az bir bileen ve ne devlet tam bir bileen olmal ne olmaldr.
Now let's think about our application states then, I'll summarize the state for the application as we plan
uygulama durumlarmz dnelim ya da burada planladmz gibi uygulama durumunu zetleyelim.
it here.
imdi bizim
Now in the state, we definitely need to manage the ingredients of the burger, so the ingredients the user
imdi devlette kesinlikle hamurun ierdii malzemeyi kullanclarn katk maddeleriyle idare
added. Ingredients will probably be some javascript object where we have something like meat, 1 times,
etmesi gerekiyor, muhtemelen ette bir kere iki kez ve benzeri bir ey bulduumuz
cheese, two times and so on,
baz javascript nesneleri olacak.
so this could be the ingredients.
Yani bu maddeler olabilir.
We also want to know whether the user is currently checking out the burger,
Ayrca kullancnn u anda burgeri kontrol ettirip tanmadn bilmek istiyoruz.
so if you clicked on purchase or not, so something like purchased and that could be true or of
Peki Chase ncesi veya satmadnz veya Per chaced gibi bir ey tkladysanz, bu doru veya tabii
course false.
ki yanl olabilir.
That actually should be almost all,
Aslnda bu neredeyse tamam olmal.
the only thing probably is a total price which we need, so that we can always see what the price is and
Tek ey, ihtiyacmz olan toplam fiyattr, bylece fiyatn ne olduunu her zaman grebiliriz ve bunu
we can dynamically calculate that
dinamik olarak hesaplayabiliriz.
and of course also output it. Now that is our state,
Ve elbette tm klar imdi bizim devletimiz.
super simple, not too difficult, right?
Sper basit deil de ok zor.
But it allows us to create a dynamic burger and output all relevant information to the user already.
Ancak bu dinamik burgeri yaratmamza ve ilgili tm bilgileri kullancya halihazrda vermemize izin veriyor.
Now where do we manage that state?
imdi nerede o lkeyi ynetiyoruz.
You could say we should manage the state in the app component here at the top but I don't agree with
bileeninde en stte yer almas gerektiini syleyebiliriz, ancak buna katlmyorum.
that,
Uygulama
we won't do it here.
Burada yapmayacaz.
Instead we should do it in the burger builder here,
Bunun yerine bunu burger yapcda yapmalyz.
why?
Niye ya.
Because the state I listed here on the right is really just related to building a burger, if we later
nk burada sada listelediim devlet, daha sonra yeni bir kontrol sayfas veya benzeri bir
add a new check out page or something like that,
ey eklersek burger yapmakla ilgilidir.
then we will basically have a page where we want to see all orders of the user and we're not interested
Sonra, temelde kullancnn tm siparilerini grmek istediimiz bir sayfaya vereceiz
of the ingredients of the burger the user currently builds.
ve tekrarlayan burgerin ierikleriyle ilgilenmiyoruz.
So managing this state on the app level isn't correct in my opinion because it doesn't affect the whole
Dolaysyla bu durumu uygulama dzeyinde ynetmek fikrime gre doru deildir, nk tm uygulama
app, it only affects this burger builder page
etkilenmez, yalnzca bu burger oluturucu sayfasn etkiler.
and for now this is going to be our whole app basically
Ve imdilik, bu temelde tm uygulamanz olacak.
but it's not how our application is going to stay once we added that checkout page and so on.
Ancak, deme sayfasn ekledikten sonra bavurunun nasl kalaca bu deil.
So the burger builder should be a stateful component,
Dolaysyla burger yapcs bir devletin tam bileeni olmaldr.
it should be a container basically
Temel olarak bir kap olmal.
so stateful,
Dolaysyla devlet dolu.
that's what the burger builder should be. All other components can be components, can be dumb components,
Avro bileenleri olmal, bileenler devlet az bileenleri dkm bileenleri olabilir.
stateless components.
Burger reticilerinin hepsi
Now the app component by default in the new project is a stateful one created with the class keyword,
imdi bileeni varsaylan olarak ve sonra proje, tam bir anahtar kelime ile tedavi edilen bir devlettir.
we can of course always leave it to be one but we can also turn it into a dumb component if we wanted
Tabii ki her zaman onu bir olmak zere brakabiliriz, ancak isterse onu
to.
dkm bileenine dntrebiliriz.
Now if we're thinking about pure components or shouldComponentUpdate,
imdi saf bileenleri dnyoruz veya bileen gncellemesi yapmalyz.
we'll both as a rule implement this as we built the application and see if we can identify some places
Hem uygulamay yaptka hem de gncelleme dngsn optimize etmemiz gereken baz yerleri belirleyebilecekmiyiz
where we need to optimize our update cycle.
diye ikimiz de bunu uygulayacak veya uygulayacaktr.
But due to the simplicity of our state and the structure of our application here, it might also be the
eye ayarlayabilecek bir dme var, bu durumda durum ok iyi olabilir.
case that we never need to implement pure component because we know that if the state or some props
Ancak arazimizin sadelii ve uygulamanzn yaps nedeniyle, saf bileeni uygulamak
changes, it did really change, that we don't have a button which might just set the state to something
zorunda kalmamamz da gerekebilir, nk devlet veya baz sahann gerekten deitii ekliyle
it was already at. So that might very well be the case,
deitiini bilmiyoruz sahneyi nceden belirlenmi bir
we'll have a look at this and take care about correctly implementing this and possibly turning something
Buna bir gz atacaz ve bunu doru bir ekilde uygulamak ve gerektiinde bireyi
into a pure component if needed.
saf bir bileene dntrmekle ilgileneceiz.
So with that, I'd say let's create a project and let's get started with that.
Bununla birlikte, bir proje oluturalm ve balayalm demeliydim.